*生日快乐*
*Happy Birthday*
好了  吹蜡烛吧  小子
All right, now you gotta blow during the that candle out, boy,
记得许愿
make sure you make a wish.
好的  好的
All right, all right.
好样的  一次吹完
There you go. First try.
15岁很重要  乔丹
15's a big year, Jordan.
是啊  这将是激情的一年
Yeah, man, it's a powerful year.
你得在教室  在赛场好好表现
You gotta do your thing in the classroom, on that court.
永远祈祷
Always preaching.
不  建议而已
Nah, that's advice.
是啊  区别很大
Yeah, it's a big difference.
-谁说的  -凡妮莎
- Says you. - Vinessa.
生日快乐  小家伙
Ah, happy birthday, lil' dog.
-你真懂我  -没错  小子
- Ooh, you know what I wanted. - Yes, boy.
看看
Look at this.
八号的  科比就穿这个
This number 8--it worked for Kobe a little bit.
我也穿这个  你肯定也能穿这个
It worked for me; it's definitely gonna work for you.
谢了  伙计
Thanks, bro.
鲁塞克要我去
Yo, um, I think Ruzek needs me
帮他做他之前提到的卧底工作
to do that undercover thing he got a bite on.
我去
Oh, I'll go.
你的肤色好像不大符合要求
Uh, actually, you might have the wrong paint job.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
那我可以留在这边帮他们吃蛋糕
I can, um, stay here and help them eat cake.
收到
Copy that.
大家伙儿
Hey, check this out.
我要敬我的小弟乔丹一杯
I wanna send a toast to my little brother Jordan, okay?
好
Oh, yeah.
让你的十五岁激情四射
Let's make 15 the most powerful year ever.
-毫无疑问  -毫无疑问
- No doubt. - No doubt.
哥们  我忘记告诉你了
Aw, dude, I forgot to tell you,
我试了你给我的烧烤酱
I tried the barbecue sauce you sent me.
-很不错吧  -得了吧
- It was good, right? - Come on, man.
总有一天会火的
Look, it's gonna be big someday,
我告诉你  只要搞点投资
I'm trying to tell you--just need to line up the financing.
你的投资就在这呢
I got your financing right here.
说到这个  你能不能给我看点货
Speaking of which, why don't you show me a few stacks?
让我放放心
Make me feel at ease.
你不相信我吗
You don't trust me?
只要涉及到钱和毒品
I don't trust my own mama when it comes to
我连我的老圣人妈妈都不信
money and drugs and she's a damn saint.
好吧  好吧
All right, all right.
我这是为了你  哥们  但是柯蒂斯可不会
Look, I'm doing this for you, bro, but Kurtis don't play.
一点都不会马虎
Like, not even a little bit.
特别是跟白小子做生意
Especially when white boys get involved.
没错  我发现了
Yeah, I picked up on that.
那天晚上我看他倒是没问题
I thought he was all right the other night though.
不  他不用白人
No, he don't dig white people.
我告诉你就是这样  比利
I'm telling you like it is, Billy,
赶紧给我看看袋子里的货
so just show me what's in the bag, please.
你懂该怎么做  你懂该怎么做
You know the drill. You know the drill.
天啊  我没武器
Oh, my goodness. I'm not holdin'.
我从来不带武器
I'm never holdin'.
我就是个掮客  就像华尔街的那种
I'm a broker, baby, like them dudes on Wall Street.
我拉生意然后抽点成而已
I set the deals up and get a little taste, that's it.
三万
30k.
没错  提醒你一下  我要...
Yes, sir. As a reminder, you know I'm--
-三千  我记得  -好
- $3,000. I remember. - Okay.
-没问题吧  -没问题
- We good? - Good.
-没问题  -好  我联系柯蒂斯
- We good. - All right, I'll call Kurtis.
好样的  走吧
My man. Let's do this.
恩格尔伍德  恩格尔伍德
Englewood, Englewood.
是啊是啊  做事不道德
Yeah, yeah, up to no good.
过来  伙计  想个新玩意吧
Come on, man. Come up with something new.
那首歌唱的根本不是...
And that song ain't even talking about--
我知道
I know.
唱的根本不是恩格尔伍德
It's talking about a different Englewood.
这个柯蒂斯小子是掌权的吗
So, this kid Kurtis is moving real weight?
他算是个新星
He's more of an up-and-comer.
他能联系到锡那罗亚贩毒团伙
He's got a direct line to the Sinaloa cartel.
拉这附近的小伙子下水可不是什么容易事
It's not easy to get a kid from this neighborhood to flip.
那是他面临十年牢狱之灾之前
Till he's staring down ten years at Stateville.
有点事
Got something to say now.
-你好  安德雷  -还好吗
- Sup, Andre? - What's happening?
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
幸会
Good to see you.
你好  大家伙
What's up, big dog?
你还好吗  比利
How you feeling, Billy?
翻译     小酸奶   风城章鱼X   小萝莉
我很好  你呢
I'm great. How you doing?
翻译     H小欠   圈圈
手机放篮子里
Cell phones in the basket.
校对     圈圈
请坐吧  伙计们
Have a seat, fellas.
时间轴     西查   chance-coco
后期     8T
总监     圈圈
西圈  对吧
So, the West Loop, huh?
那是个未开发的大市场
It's a huge, untapped market.
一群有钱白人佬想要狂欢
Tons of rich white dudes looking to party.
问题是那里没什么高质量的好货
The only problem is there's no quality product there.
艾迪抽成多少
What's Eddie's cut?
三千
Three grand.
我忘了
I forgot, uh...
你俩怎么认识的来着
How'd you two meet?
芭蕾
Ballet.
什么
What?
就是有迪斯科舞球和跳舞管子的那种地方
Yeah, the spot with the disco balls and the dancer poles.
28街和杰弗森路交叉口
On 28th and Jefferson, you know?
那种芭蕾啊
Oh, that kind of ballet.
我当时在泡其中一个芭蕾舞者
I was dating one of the ballerinas.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
差不多吧
Uh, sorta.
我得时不时给她点
I had to pay her a little something-something
小好处  不过她值那个价
from time to time, but she was worth every penny.
她真是个狐狸精
Yeah, she was a fox.
很高兴你们俩能对上眼
Well, I'm glad you two hit it off.
幸会  比利
It's nice to see you again, Billy.
怎么了
What happened?
我不知道啊  本来感觉不错  然后突然
I don't know. It felt good, and then bam,
他就走了  会面结束
he was out the door. Meeting over.
你觉得他们认出凯文了吗
You think they made Kev?
不会  我一直盯着我的芝士汉堡
Nah, I mean, I was staring at my cheeseburger the whole time.
谁知道  可能只是他很小心
Who knows, maybe he's just careful.
还好艾迪没有发现异样
Hey, good news is Eddie's still on board.
他刚发信息给我  要我几小时后
He just texted me, wants me to swing by his house
去他那儿
in a few hours.
很好  继续伪装  凯文  时刻留意
Good, play it out. Kev, keep an eye on him.
伙计  别太着急
Hey, man, don't push it.
我们还能找别的毒贩
There's other dealers we can work with.
那可都不是柯蒂斯
Not like Kurtis, there's not.
是吗  他为什么那么特别
Oh, yeah? Why's he so special?
他喜欢杀人  就像他喜欢贩毒一样
He likes killing as much as he likes dealing.
他就是喜欢
He enjoys it.
艾迪  你在哪里
Eddie, where you at, man?
第三通电话了
Call number three.
听着  我有点紧张了
Listen, I'm getting a little nervous.
不知道你有没有注意到我是
I don't know if you noticed I'm a preppy white dude
来自北边郊区的白小子  赶紧给我回电
from the northern suburbs, so you need to hit me back.
我在你家门前
I'm at your door.
艾迪
Eddie?
Eddie. Hey!
-凯文  看好前门  -收到
- Kev, cover the front. - Copy that.
凯文  叫救护车  快点
Kev, roll an ambo. Right now.
-艾迪  艾迪  -收到
- Eddie? Eddie? - Copy.
怎么了  伙计  谁干的
Hey, what happened, man? Who did this?
天啊  艾迪
Jesus. Eddie.
我们先得止血  坚持住  伙计
We're gonna stop the bleeding. You just hold on, man.
艾迪  很抱歉  但我是警察
Eddie, listen, I'm sorry to tell you this, but I'm a cop.
我已经叫人来帮忙了
I got help on the way right now, okay?
你得坚持住
You just gotta stay strong.
不  艾迪  别动  别动
No, Eddie, stop, man. Stop. Stop.
-你是个警察  你...  -对不起  对不起
- You're a cop! You're a... - I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
你得告诉我  告诉我是谁干的
You gotta talk to me. Tell me who did this.
是柯蒂斯吗
Was it Kurtis?
你的...
What's...
真名是什么
your real name?
是亚当
It's Adam.
亚当·鲁塞克
Adam Ruzek.
哥们  听我说
Hey, brother. Listen, look at me.
谁干的
Who did it?
告诉我  是柯蒂斯干的吗
Tell me, was it Kurtis who did this?
是柯蒂斯吗
Was it Kurtis?
不
No.
我不要这样去死
I ain't going out like that,
亚当
Adam.
什么样  哥们
Like what, man?
像个
Like...
像个告密者
Like a snitch.
别啊  哥们  别啊
Nah, man, no, no, no.
艾迪  别这样  哥们
Eddie, come on, man.
艾迪
Eddie?
撑住啊  哥们
Come on, man!
芝加哥
警署
第五季
第四集
什么情况
What do we got?
胸口两枪  9毫米
Two to the chest. Nine millimeter.
弹壳就在这
The casings are right here.
-找到枪了吗  -还没
- Find a gun? - Not yet.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
这就是柯蒂斯或者他手下的人干的
This was Kurtis or somebody that worked for him.
肯定是
It had to be.
那我们跟着证据走吧
Well, now we follow the evidence.
带上厄普顿和霍斯特德  挨家盘问吧
Grab Upton and Halstead. Start knocking.
我们需要目击证人
We need witnesses.
好
Yeah.
我到的时候他还活着
He was alive when I got here.
他还活着  就躺在那
He was alive, right there.
我想救他  就告诉了他我是警察
I was trying to help him. Told him I was a cop.
他看我的那个眼神啊
The way he looked at me, man.
推开我的手
Pushed my hands away.
他知道他为什么被杀了  因为我被识破了
He knew why he got shot... 'cause I got made...
而他却付出了代价
And he picked up the tab.
我明白
I understand.
我明白  你真的喜欢艾迪
I get it, I mean, you really liked Eddie.
但这不是你的责任  哥们
But this isn't on you, dog.
不是你开的枪
You didn't pull that trigger.
-明白吗  -谢了哥们
- All right? - Thanks, bro.
我们会抓住他的
We'll get him.
我什么都没听见  什么都没看见
I didn't see anything or hear anything.
你就住街对面  离他家才20英尺
You live across the street, 20 feet from his house.
我在看电视呢  音量开得很大
I was watching TV, had the volume up.
还有事吗
Anything else?
你认识艾迪吧
You knew Eddie, right?
他是好人吗
Yeah? Was he a good guy?
-大好人  -是吗
- Great guy. - Yeah?
那你为什么不帮我们抓住杀他的凶手
Why not help us find the man who killed him?
因为那不是我的工作
Not my job.
这么说他被杀你无所谓了
Oh, you're okay with him getting killed?
我可没说无所谓
Didn't say I was okay with it.
我只是说不是我的工作
I said it's not my job.
有区别的
There's a difference.
其实没有
Not really.
你和他家就住邻居吧
I mean, you live right next door, right?
你什么都没听见吗
You didn't hear anything?
请你告诉我们你听见了什么
All right, hey, just tell us what you heard, please.
我什么都没听到
I didn't hear anything.
你什么都没听到
You didn't hear anything?
好吧
All right.
-你见过这个人吗  -没见过
- Have you seen this guy? - No.
你都没看他的照片
You didn't even look yet.
你见过这个人吗
Have you seen this guy?
-没有  -从来没见过
- No. - Never?
从来没有
Never.
真是太谢谢你了
Thank you so much.
"禁止告密"的风刮得越来越紧了
This no snitch thing gets worse and worse.
别人不信任你  就不会合作
There's no trust. There's no cooperation.
还记得几年前他们至少
Remember a few years back when they at least
装模作样地看一眼  然后还正经撒个谎
gave a courtesy look, and then a respectful lie?
记得
Yeah.
这是检测摄像头的录像
So this is spotter-cam video.
不是很清楚  但这时枪声响起
It's not perfect, but here's the shot.
镜头旋转
Swivels.
拍到了这个人
There's our guy.
看起来就像柯蒂斯
Yeah. Sure looks like Kurtis.
身高体重都差不多
Mm, about the same height, same weight.
但我们看不清他的脸
Yeah, but we can't see his face.
肯定不足以申请搜查证
Definitely not enough for a warrant.
不过足够你带上安东尼奥去敲他的门了
It's enough for you to grab Antonio and pay him a visit.
好
Yup.
所以是这么回事  柯蒂斯打死了艾迪
So, what happened, Kurtis shoots Eddie,
然后从后门跑了
he goes running out the back?
是  但是我看到的沾血足迹
Yeah, but the bloody footprints that I saw--
是从前门出去的
they went out the front door.
可能有两名枪手
It could be two shooters.
一个从前门走了  一个从后门走了
One goes out the front, the other goes out the back.
你们俩  去那家餐厅
Hey, you two, head over to that restaurant
问问怎么回事
and figure out what happened, will you?
-好  -有什么情况惊动他们了
- Okay. - Something spooked these guys.
柯蒂斯·华盛顿  我们是芝加哥警察
Kurtis Washington, Chicago PD.
我们来问问你一个朋友的事情
We'd like to talk to you about a friend of yours,
艾迪·格林
Eddie Greene.
无可奉告
Got nothing to say.
他昨晚被杀了
He was killed last night.
无可奉告
Got nothing to say.
我们有理由相信
We have reason to believe
当晚早些时候你和他在一起
that you were with him earlier that evening.
也许你可以帮我们找到杀害他的凶手
Maybe you could help us find the man who killed him
毕竟你们是朋友
since you two are friends?
无可奉告
Got nothing to say.
你知道监测探头是什么吗
Do you know what a spotter cam is?
-无可奉告  -好吧
- I got nothing to say. - Okay.
是一种特别厉害的新科技
It's this amazing new piece of technology.
只要听到枪响  镜头就会
When a gun is fired, a video camera just
自动旋转  朝向枪声传来的方向
automatically swivels towards the direction of the sound.
而逃跑的那个人
And the dude running away
看起来和你可像了
sure looks a lot like you.
我说了  警官
Like I said, officer...
无可奉告
I got nothing to say.
好吧  没事  我们会回来的
Okay, don't worry. We'll be back.
有什么需要帮忙吗
How can I help you?
我们想谈谈你这的一个常客
We wanna talk to you about one of your regular customers,
柯蒂斯·华盛顿
Kurtis Washington.
鸡块  超辣  炸薯条
Chicken, extra spicy, French fries.
再来杯柠檬冰茶
Arnold Palmer.
多加柠檬少放茶
More lemonade than tea.
我们更想知道他的生意往来
We're more interested in his business dealings
而不是他喜欢吃什么
than his food choices.
你们这有厕所吗
You got a men's room?
多谢
Thanks.
那安德雷·沃克呢
What about Andre Walker?
火腿奶酪三明治  多加奶酪
Ham and cheese sandwich, extra swiss.
又说回吃的了
Back to food, huh?
我是干这行的  吃的
That's my business. Food.
别的我不管
Nothing else.
容我说一句
May I say...
你可能是我见过的最漂亮的女警了
You might be the prettiest damn police I've ever seen.
才可能
Might be?
好吧  你就是
Okay, you are.
这才像话
That's better.
柯蒂斯  安德雷昨天和艾迪·格林一起来了
So, Kurtis and Andre came in yesterday with Eddie Greene
还有另外一个人  白人
and another guy. White guy.
不认识艾迪
Don't know Eddie.
也不知道什么白人
Or the white dude.
发生什么意外情况了吗
Anything unusual happen?
根本没注意他们来过
Didn't even notice they were here.
你很厉害
You're good.
所以我活得好好的  宝贝儿
That's why I'm still standing, baby.
多谢
Thank you.
谢谢
你的意见非常宝贵
Your insights and observations were invaluable.
在餐馆找到了反监视装置
Found a counter-surveillance device in the restaurant.
那种你可以在什么间谍商店
The kind you can buy for five bucks
花5块钱就买到的玩意儿
at some half-assed spy store.
肯定是读取了鲁塞克无线电的传送信息
Must've read the transmission from Ruzek's wire,
所以柯蒂斯中止了见面
so Kurtis cut the meeting short.
他们可能觉得艾迪是内应
They probably thought Eddie was snitching--
在办案子  所以朝他开枪
working a case, so he popped him,
在胸口上来了两枪
Two in the chest.
技术人员提取了两枚新指纹
Hey, techs lifted two fresh prints--
一个是在艾迪卧室啤酒瓶上的
one off of a beer bottle in Eddie's living room
另一个是前门把手上的
and the other off the front door knob.
这两枚指纹都与罗兰德·加瑞特的一致
Both are a match to Roland Garrett.
男性  黑人  36岁  一项重罪指控
Male, black, 36. One felony charge.
持械严重伤害罪
Aggravated assault with a firearm.
现在就去追踪他
Track him down, now.
-罗兰德·加瑞特  -什么事
- Roland Garrett? - Yes?
我们是芝加哥警察
Chicago PD.
-举起手  -发生什么事了
- Keep your hands up. - Man, what's going on?
我们得谈谈  到我这边来
We need to talk. Step down to me.
-谈什么  -艾迪·格林  转过身
- About what? - Eddie Greene. Turn around.
昨晚有人杀了他
Someone killed him last night.
我知道
I know.
你知道他死了啊
Oh, you know he's dead.
是啊
Yeah.
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
我的指纹在啤酒瓶上  然后呢
My fingerprints are on a beer bottle, so what?
我们把啤酒瓶装起来的时候  还是冰的
Well, the beer was still cold when we bagged it.
说明你哥哥遇害时你在现场
That means you were there when your brother got shot.
要么就是你杀了他
So, either A, you did it,
要么就是你看到了凶手
or B, you saw who did.
或者  我已经离开了
Or C, I was there,
但是不是我干的  也没看到是谁干的
but I didn't do it and I didn't see it.
-嘿  -老兄  还好吗  凯文
- Hey. - Bro, what's up, Kevin?
你还好吗
You good?
罗兰德在我那个街区开了家小店
Roland owns the mini mart on my block.
是个好人
Good people.
我们只是想知道事情经过
Um, so, yeah, we just wanna know what happened.
实际上我们知道的越多  越能帮到你
And actually the more we know, the more we can help out,
所以你知道些什么  老兄
so, what you know, dog?
好吧
Okay.
我是去过
I was there.
我去见艾迪  去打了招呼
I went to see Eddie, you know, to say hi.
去表示哀悼
Pay my condolences,
因为他父亲过世后我就没见过他
'cause I ain't seen him since his pop passed.
我们同母异父
We got the same mother, different fathers.
知道了
Right.
然后发生了什么
So, what happened?
我们当时在叙旧
We were catching up.
艾迪他很紧张
Eddie was, uh... He was nervous.
说他和别人有交易
Said he had some deal with somebody
有人被吓到了什么的
and somebody got spooked or something like that,
我不清楚  没怎么注意
I don't know. I don't really pay attention.
我爱艾迪  但他总是犯事
You know, I loved Eddie, but he's always hustling.
之后有个人来了
Anyway, some-- some guy shows up.
但是从后门来的  我没看到
But he--he knocked at the back door; I didn't see him.
我去厨房做了三明治
Uh, I went to the kitchen to make a sandwich.
-你没看到他吗  -没有
- You didn't see him? - No, sir.
11号鞋吗
Size 11?
对
Yeah.
现场有你的脚印  罗兰德
We got your footprint, Roland.
血脚印
Bloody footprints.
说明你当时在艾迪尸体边
That means you were near Eddie's body.
是的
Yeah.
在那人开枪打了艾迪后  我...
After the dude shot Eddie, I...
他从后门跑了
He ran out the back door.
所以我走到艾迪身边
So I walked over to Eddie,
看到他被枪击了
and I saw he was shot.
他当时...
He was...
他向门爬过去
He was crawling towards the door.
我吓坏了
I got scared.
所以...
So...
所以我从前门跑了
So, I ran out the front door.
但是2分钟后我打了911
But yo, I-I called 911 like two minutes later.
你们可以去查记录
Y'all can check the records.
我们会的
Yeah, we will.
听着...
Listen...
我得问一句
I-I gotta ask this.
为什么不去救你哥哥
Why not help save your brother's life?
我是个卖安全套和糖果的  老兄
I sell--I sell condoms and candy bars, homey.
我不知道怎么去救人
I'm not equipped to save nobody's life.
但如果让你看照片  你能认出凶手
But if you saw photos, you could recognize the guy.
不
No!
好吗  我没有...
Right? I didn't--
没有看到凶手的脸
I didn't see his face.
这是你的亲兄弟  罗兰德
This is your flesh and blood, Roland.
我知道
I know.
但他已经走了
But he's gone.
而我还得在那儿生活
I still gotta live there.
-凯文  你知道这是什么意思  -知道
- Kev, you know how it is. - Yeah.
我很清楚
You know, I know.
但这次不同
There's a difference this time.
好吗  现在你对面是我
All right? This is me.
我可以罩着你
And I can help you on this side.
不会有事的  老兄
You're good, bro.
我...
I...
我不是英雄  凯文
I ain't no hero, Kev.
只是一个付着房租的兄弟
Just another brother trying to pay his rent,
也许时不时找个乐子
maybe have a little fun,
勉强度日
stay above ground.
我不管你多讨厌警察
I don't care how much you hate the police.
如果有家人卷进来  你就得澄清
If you got family involved, you gotta come clean.
受害人自己都不愿告诉我是谁干的
The victim himself wouldn't even give me a name
他就躺在那儿  最后一句话就是
and he's lying there dying and the last thing he says is
"我不是告密者"
"I ain't no snitch."
把真相带进坟墓
Talk about taking it to your grave.
伙计们  调到了案发那晚的
Hey, guys, found some video surveillance
监控摄像
from the night of the murder.
不是很清楚  但是拍到的远距离画面
It's not perfect, but it shows a distant image
让我们确信是柯蒂斯·华盛顿
of the man we believe to be Kurtis Washington
在艾迪家两个街区外上了一辆宝马
hopping into a BMW two blocks from Eddie's house.
牌照查到了吗
You make out the plate?
已经在查了
Already ran it.
注册在玛雅·斯普里格斯名下  她是
It's registered to Maya Spriggs, girlfriend of
安德雷·沃克的女朋友  三个孩子的妈妈
Andre Walker, mother of his three children.
所以安德雷是接应的司机  那就说通了
Oh, so Andre was the getaway driver, that makes sense.
他们是同伙
They're partners.
去找到那辆车  也许能找到血迹
All right, get that car. Maybe we can find some blood.
这是你的车的搜查令
There's a warrant for the car.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-宝贝  那是我的车  -没事的  宝贝
- Baby, that's my car. - I got this, baby.
等等  他为什么要这样
Wait, why does he need to?
去看孩子
Go back to the kids.
让他们离警察远远的
Keep them away from all this police harassment.
好啊  比利
'Sup, Billy?
好久不见
Long time no see.
有何贵干
What you doing over here, huh?
还以为你住在西圈
Thought you lived in the West Loop.
你说过  那边有一个巨大的
Word is, there's a huge,
还没开发的市场
untapped market for blow up there?
告诉你  艾迪他根本不知道我是警察
Just so you know, Eddie-- he had no idea I was a cop.
他根本不知道
No idea.
其实我喜欢艾迪这个人
You know, I liked Eddie.
柯蒂斯也是
Kurtis did too.
你害他丧命  我们感觉很糟糕
We feel real bad you got his ass popped.
你还是自求多福吧  安德雷
You better watch yourself, Andre.
我听着像是招供了
Sounds like a confession to me.
我谁也没杀
I ain't killed nobody.
我也不知道谁杀了谁
And I don't know nobody who killed nobody.
但这里消息传得很快
But word gets out around here.
艾迪这样的告密者很快会被处理掉
And snitches like Eddie get dealt with real fast.
我们走吧
Well, let's go.
听你女朋友的
Listen to your girlfriend,
比利
Billy.
待会儿见
We'll see you soon.
安德雷的宝马很干净  到处都没发现血迹
Andre's BMW is clean. No blood evidence anywhere.
是吗  那艾迪家呢
Yeah? What about Eddie's house?
技术人员还在查  目前没发现
Techs are still working on it--so far, nothing.
总该有点什么吧
There's gotta be something.
指纹  毛发
A print? A hair?
真的吗
Seriously?
我们知道柯蒂斯杀了他
We know that Kurtis popped him.
也知道安德雷开着宝马接应他
We know that Andre picked him up in the BMW.
对  但知道没有用
Yeah, well, knowing doesn't mean a damn thing.
赶紧出去找证据
So, go out there and find something.
天啊
God.
亚当
Hey, Adam.
你得看开点
You gotta let it go.
无论艾迪是不是好人
I mean, good guy or not,
既然干这行  他就知道有风险
Eddie was in the game. He knew the risk.
是
Yeah.
我的线人刚告诉我  安德雷的女人玛雅
One of my CIs just told me that Andre's girl, Maya,
开了一家没有执照的美容院卖毒品
deals dope out of a unlicensed beauty salon
她已经有两条前科了
and she's got two priors.
-可以利用  -是的
- That's something. - Yeah.
带上伯吉斯和厄普顿
Take Burgess and Upton.
-走吧  -好的  收到
- Let's go. - All right, copy that.
芝加哥警察
Chicago PD!
所有人都把手举起来
Everyone show us your hands now.
-什么情况  -手举起来  我们有搜查令
- What the hell is going on? - Hands up, we have a warrant.
玛雅  对吗  转过去
Maya, right? Turn around for me.
转过去  我就是想看看
Turn around for me. Just wanna see what kind
你在这里卖的是什么美容产品
of beauty products you're pushing out of this joint.
不好意思  女士们
All right, sorry about that, ladies.
走吧
Come on now.
宝贝
Baby.
宝贝  来捞我
Baby, come get me.
我会的  安心等着
Look, I will. Just sit tight.
要求见律师  嘴巴闭紧
Ask for a lawyer and keep your damn mouth shut.
这是骚扰
This is harassment!
你知道吧
You know that, right?
安德雷
Andre.
你的妞开了家无证的美容院又不是我们的错
It's not our fault your lady runs a salon without a license.
而且她还卖毒品
And sells blow in her spare time.
你们找到了什么
What'd you find, huh?
几克毒品  还是八球
What, a couple grams? Eight ball or something?
她什么都没卖
She don't move no product.
问题是  她有两次前科
The problem is, she's got two priors.
加上这次指控  她走定了
With this new charge, she's going away.
她太失败了  被抓三次
She's a three-time loser.
你孩子的母亲
Mother of your children.
当然了  除非你有事跟我们说
Unless, of course, you got something to tell us.
我不知道  可能有什么
Something that might, I don't know,
让我们想放弃这个案子的事
inspire us to drop the case?
没有
Nope.
什么都没有
Not a damn thing.
我反正已经腻味了她的屁股
You know, I'm getting sick and tired of her ass anyway.
其实  你们帮了我个忙
Truth is, you're doing me a favor.
真是条汉子
Wow, hell of a guy--
闭嘴  贱人  我没跟...
Shut up, bitch, I wasn't talking to--
你很能说啊  你知道吧
You got a smart mouth, you know that!
站起来  再说一遍  说
Stand up! Say that again, right now!
够了
Enough!
我把警徽收起来
I'll take this badge off.
咱俩现在就可以打一架
You and I could do this right now, man!
拜托  海莉
Come on, Hailey,
你什么情况
what the hell is wrong with you?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你什么毛病
What is wrong with you?
改造  政府监管  独立审计
Reform, federal oversight, independent auditors.
你不能因为别人惹你生气你就打人
You can't just hit people because they piss you off.
反正不能当着我的面
Not in front of me, anyway.
上车
Get in the car.
安德雷不会松口
Andre's not gonna flip.
他一点都没退缩
He didn't even flinch.
在皮尔森  大家不会乱说话
In Pilsen, they don't talk
因为他们担心被举报
'cause they're afraid of getting deported.
在恩格尔伍德  大家担心会中枪
In Englewood, they're afraid of getting shot.
我明天会晚点来
Look, I'll be in late tomorrow.
有个家长会我必须得去
I have a parent-teacher conference thing I have to be at.
警长  让我再找一次罗兰德
Yo, Sarge, let me grab Roland one more time.
我觉得他内心深处是想说的
I mean, I think deep down he wants to talk.
如果再让他想想  我可以说服他
I can convince him to if he can just wrap his head around it.
有什么可想的
Not a lot to wrap your head around.
有人朝你哥哥胸口开了两枪
Someone shoots your brother twice in the chest,
你还不废了他
you bury his ass.
没那么简单
See, it's deeper than that.
我的天啊  那是他哥
Oh, my God, it was his brother.
有人杀了他哥
Somebody shot his brother,
只有他能帮我们
he's the only person that can help us,
他却要保护凶手
and he's gonna protect the killer?
我不是这个意思
That's not what I'm saying.
我是说  我们那边
What I'm saying is, where I come from,
还有罗兰德住的那边  不相信警察的人
or where Roland lives, if you don't trust the cops,
-是不会配合的  -这就叫懦夫
- you're not gonna cooperate. - It's called being a coward--
别再废话了  听到了吗
Enough of this crap, you hear me?
我不关心谁对谁错
I don't care about what's right.
我只关心破案
I care about making this case.
明白吗
You understand?
明白
Yeah.
很好
All right, good.
-那就去找罗兰德  -好的
- So, talk to Roland. - A'ight.
如果他肯说  也许我们可以提供证人保护
He comes forward, maybe we can offer witness protection.
我们可能得另作打算了
We might have to come up with another plan.
怎么了
What's going on?
男性  黑人  三十岁不到  胸口两枪
Male, black, late 20s. Two to the chest.
-被害人姓名  -罗兰德·加瑞特
- Victim's name-- - Roland Garrett.
老大  地上有两个九毫米的弹壳
Hey, boss--two nine millimeter shells on the floor.
监控呢
Surveillance video?
有  这里有两个摄像头  但都坏了
Yeah, there's two cameras in here. but neither one of them work.
-收银机呢  -满的
- The register? - It's full.
凶手直接走进来  开了两枪  就走了
Shooter just walked in, took two shots, and walked out.
我们都知道是柯蒂斯干的  对吗
This was Kurtis. We all know that, right?
他肯定是知道罗兰德当时在艾迪家
He obviously figured out Roland was at Eddie's house
保险起见  他就让他闭嘴了
and didn't wanna roll the dice he'd keep his mouth shut.
巡警找到一个目击证人
Hey, patrol found a witness
说他们看到有人从现场逃走
who says they saw a guy run from the scene,
把什么东西丢在楼后面的垃圾箱了
drop something in the dumpster behind the building.
去看看
Go check it out.
你俩在附近问问  看看有没有发现
You two start knocking, see what you can find.
肯定有人看到
Someone had to see something.
是的  但是会有人跟我们说吗
Yeah, but will someone talk to us?
好的  走吧
You got it. Come on.
凯文
Kev.
那是乔丹吗
Is that Jordan?
该死  等等
Damn. Hold on.
乔丹
Jordan!
你在这里干什么
Yo, what the hell are you doing out here, man?
过来
Come here.
这是什么情况  老弟
Man, what the hell is going on, bro?
这他妈都快十一点了
It's damn near 11:00.
你在外面干什么
What you doing out here?
我刚才从米歇尔家回来  然后...
I was walking back from Michelle's house, and...
我们在学习  我睡着了...
we were studying and I fell asleep--
睡着个鬼  乔丹
Fell asleep my ass, Jordan.
我们早就说过  兄弟
Now we've already had this conversation, dog,
我是你哥  我最不想看到...
I'm your big brother and the last thing I--
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
怎么了
What happened?
情况不妙
Nothing good.
哥
Bro...
那个是罗兰德吗
That's Roland?
是的
Yeah.
我挺喜欢他的  哥
I liked him, bro.
我跟他说我进了篮球队
I mean, when I told him I made the basketball team,
他送了我一堆吃的
he gave me a bunch of free food.
还说他争取去看几场比赛
He even said he'd make it to a few games.
谁开的枪
Who shot him?
一个当地毒贩
A local dope dealer.
罗兰德看到了不该看到的事
Roland saw something he shouldn't have saw.
我们离开这里吧
Come on. Let's get out of here.
一个目击证人看到一个不明身份男性
All right, an eyewitness saw an unidentified male
从现场逃跑  并把什么扔进了垃圾桶里
flee from the scene, toss an object into a dumpster.
霍斯特德警探从案发现场一个街区外
Detective Halstead recovered that object one block
找到了那个东西  是一把九毫米手枪
from the scene-a Glock, nine millimeter.
-弹道检测呢  -跟杀艾迪·格林的是同一把
- Ballistics? - Same weapon used in the Eddie Greene homicide.
-指纹呢  -没有
- Prints? - Negative.
枪跟柯蒂斯·华盛顿
Does it connect back to Kurtis Washington
或安德雷·沃克等任何这个帮派的人有关系吗
or Andre Walker or anyone involved with this gang?
没有  枪是威斯康辛一个注册枪主那被偷的
No, it was stolen from a registered owner in Wisconsin.
没有法医证据  没有目击证人
No forensics, no witnesses...
我知道  但一切的源头都是
Yeah, I get it, but it all goes back
他们跟鲁塞克的那次卧底会面
to that undercover meeting with Ruzek,
对了  我们有那个的录像
which we got on tape, by the way.
听我说
Listen.
柯蒂斯发现不对就中止了会面
Kurtis gets spooked, calls off the meet.
两小时后  艾迪胸口中两枪被害
Two hours later, Eddie gets popped, two in the chest.
第二天  唯一的目击者
The next day, the only eyewitness,
他弟弟罗兰德  也胸口中两枪被杀
his brother Roland, gets popped two in the chest.
两起谋杀案的武器相同
Same weapon both hits.
我同意你的说法
I'm with you.
柯蒂斯是抢手  安德雷负责开车逃跑
Kurtis is the shooter, Andre drove the getaway car.
都没问题  但是
Check, check. But...
我们还是没有足够证据进行下一步
We still don't have enough to move forward.
很抱歉  汉克
I'm sorry, Hank.
申请到搜查令了吗
Any luck with the warrant?
没有  瓦尔迪兹说我们需要更多证据
Nah, Valdez says we need more.
-一点都不新奇啊  -是啊
- Ah, what else is new, right? - Yep.
你的家长会怎么样
Hey, how was that parent-teacher conference?
很棒
It was great.
伊娃成绩很好  全优
Eva's doing really well. Getting all A's.
代我打个招呼
Tell her I said hey.
好
Yeah.
-亚当  -什么
- Adam. - Yeah?
过来一下
Give me a second.
什么事  老大
What's up, boss?
今早有人因为你打电话来
Got a call about you this morning.
有人看到你揍了安德雷·沃克
Someone saw you punch Andre Walker.
有人投诉了
That someone filed a beef.
内务部正式展开了调查
IAD's opened an official investigation.
老大  那个混蛋安德雷  他得寸进尺...
Boss, this prick Andre, he was pushing his luck--
你先别说了
Stop talking now.
他拒不配合  反抗执法
An active resister refused to comply with your orders.
他想制服你
He tried to overpower you.
为了保护自己和他人
In order to protect yourself and others,
你才使用武力  夺回现场控制权
you used physical force to regain control of the situation.
明白了
All right, copy that.
至于厄普顿  就看你了
As to Upton, that's on you.
好
All right.
洒了咖啡
Spilled coffee.
我会记得给自己买个严实一点的盖子
Memo to self-invent a lid that doesn't drip.
话说  昨天的事
Hey, so, listen, that thing from yesterday--
变得有点严重了
it's become a little bit of a situation.
有人看到了发生的事  投诉了我
Somebody saw what happened, they filed a report,
所以我得处理一下
Now I got a CR to deal with.
我想确保你和我统一战线
I just wanna make sure you and I are on the same page.
统一战线
Same page.
我知道你知道我的意思
I know you know what I mean.
我要考虑一下
I'm gonna have to think about it.
说实话
Just shooting straight, man.
现在到处有手机和摄像头
There's iPhones and cameras everywhere.
扯个谎不是那么容易的事了
It's not so easy to just make up a lie anymore.
我知道有很多好警察
And I know a lot of good coppers
因为作伪证丢了饭碗
that have been stripped for falsifying--
你该怎么办就怎么办吧  厄普顿
No, you do what you gotta do, Upton.
找到了线索  在小超市一个街区外
Caught a break. Found some surveillance footage
找到了一个摄像头的监控录像
from a camera about a block away from the mini mart.
谢了
Thanks, man.
这绝对是柯蒂斯
That is Kurtis, no doubt.
那是因为你知道是他
That's 'cause you know it's him.
陪审团会觉得那只是一个穿着连帽衫的黑人瘦子
If you're in a jury, that's a skinny man, black, wearing a hoodie.
好  我来试试
All right, let me play with it,
看看能不能找到更好的角度
see if I can get a better angle.
那是枪
Well, there's the gun.
正常画面再播一遍
All right, play it again, regular size.
停住  看到了吗
All right, hold it. Stop. See that?
这里还有人
There's someone else there.
可能是安德雷在放风
Yeah, probably Andre being a lookout.
我来放大一下看看  等一下
Let me mess with it. Hold up.
我只能看出他的运动鞋
Yeah, all I can make out is his sneaker.
说实话
Straight up.
你看到把枪扔进垃圾桶那个人的脸了
You saw the face of the man who threw the gun in the dumpster.
是
Yes.
如果我给你看照片  你能认出来吗
If I showed you photos, you can identify the guy?
我是能  但是
I mean, I can, but...
哥  你看到罗兰德的下场了
Bro, look what happened to Roland.
你看到他的下场了
Look what happened to him.
他死了  哥们
I mean, he winded up dead, dude.
大家都恨告密的人  你知道
People hate snitches and you know that.
我明白  但那种事不会发生在你身上
I understand that, but that's not gonna happen to you, okay?
我不会让那种事发生在你身上
I'm not gonna let that happen to you.
我知道你不会  但还是有可能发生
I mean, I know you wouldn't but it still could.
你想让我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
首先  你没有做错什么  乔丹
First of all, you didn't do anything wrong, Jordan.
所以在我看来  你不是告密者
So, as far as I'm concerned, you're not a snitch.
你很勇敢
You're brave.
你愿意帮忙把一个坏人
You're willing to help put away a man who did a bad thing
绳之以法  所以
to a very good person, so...
我就只想让你有自尊
All I want you to do is have self-respect.
我想让你余生能够
I want you to be able to look in the mirror
每天看着镜子
every day for the rest of your life
知道自己在关键时刻做了正确的事
and know that you did the right thing when it mattered.
这是我唯一的心愿
That's all I want.
你还好吧
You all good, right?
嗯
Yeah.
好
乔丹
Jordan.
你好  乔丹
Hi, Jordan.
我是安娜·瓦尔迪兹  州检察官办公室的
I'm Anna Valdez; I'm with the State's Attorney's office.
你哥哥告诉我你看到有人把一把枪丢进垃圾桶了
Your brother told me you saw someone toss a gun into a dumpster.
是
Yeah.
我听到了枪声  然后
I heard gunshots, and...
有个人从商店里出来
Then this man came out of the store,
把一把枪丢进了一个绿色的大垃圾桶
and threw a gun into this big, green dumpster.
终于找到突破口了
Finally caught a lucky break.
我们先安顿一下吧
Let's get you set up in here, all right?
-你饿吗  -嗯
- You hungry? -Yeah.
你确定吗
You sure about all this?
不确定
No.
那你为什么这么做
Why the hell are you doing it?
因为这是正确的事
Because it's the right thing to do.
别管正确不正确
Forget what's right.
要为自己和家人考虑
You do what's best for you and your family.
这才是正确的
That's what's right.
我知道  谢谢
Yeah. Appreciate it.
好  如果你看到
Okay, if you see the man
那个丢枪的人了  那就说出来  好吗
who tossed the gun into the dumpster, just say so, okay?
不是
No.
是
Yeah.
他
Him.
谢谢  乔丹
Thank you, Jordan.
打印搜查令吧
Type up the warrant.
我会联系值班法官
I'll get in touch with the duty judge.
为你骄傲  乔丹
Proud of you, Jordan.
5021C  呼叫总部
5021 Charlie, 10-1, 10-1.
有人向警方开枪  黑人男性
Shots fired at the police. Male, black.
正往巷子跑去
Hoofing it down the alley.
收到  5021C  现场开枪
Copy that, 5021 Charlie. Shots fired.
站住
Stop!
疑犯刚跑进卢米斯街的一条巷子
Offender just ran into an alley off of Loomis,
往西跑了
headed west.
捡起来
Pick it up.
拜托你捡起来
Please, pick it up.
凯文
Kevin.
他的脚踝处可能藏着另一把枪
He might have another weapon on his ankle.
小心点
Be careful.
没事  凯文  有我在
It's all right, Kevin, I got you.
退下
Stand down.
起来
Get up.
你因为谋杀罗兰德·加瑞特被捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Roland Garrett.
走
Let's go.
走吧
Come on.
我告诉过你你比看上去跑得快吗
Have I ever told you you're faster than you look?
你觉得我超重了吗
You think I'm overweight?
哥们  我需要破了这个案子
Dude, I needed this.
谢谢了  你今天做得太棒了
Thanks, man. You did a hell of a job today.
不客气
Hey, appreciate that.
请你喝酒
Buy you a drink?
这次先算了
Not this time.
我应该带凡妮莎和乔丹去吃晚餐
I think I should probably take Vinessa and Jordan to dinner.
-说得对  -恭喜
- Fair enough. - Congratulations.
我听说你们今天案子办得很漂亮
I hear you boys had a nice pinch today.
谢谢
Appreciate that.
还有很长的路要走
Long way to walk for an attaboy.
还是需要锻炼的
Nah. Need the exercise.
一直坐等  可能会
All this sitting around can actually
让寿命缩短20%
shorten your life span by 20%.
但是我有事跟你商量
But, uh, there is something we need to discuss.
私下里
In private.
好  请吧
Okay. After you.
-恭喜  -再见
- Congratulations. - Sir.
明天见
I'll see you guys in the morning.
谢谢  老大  晚安
Thanks, boss. Have a good night.
-莫利  -好
- Molly's? - Yes.
豆腐鸡
Tofu chicken.
中医
Chinese medicine.
推特
Twitter.
我不明白你在说什么  丹尼
I'm not sure where you're going with this, Denny,
不过我很感兴趣
but I am intrigued.
我只是在列举我觉得
I am just listing a few things that I'm guessing
你认为可笑的事
you think are ridiculous.
还行吧
So far, so good.
还有一个
I got one more for you too.
警察改革
Police reform.
你知道你的人鲁塞克
You know your man Rowzek?
鲁塞克
Ruzek.
那天对他的投诉撤销了
The case we filed the other day just went away.
唯一的目击者  一个叫伊冯·华莱士的年轻女性
Seems the only witness, a young woman named Yvonne Wallace,
改了主意
changed her mind.
我第一次听说
It's news to me.
是吗
Is that right?
还是一开始就合作比较好  汉克
You know, it's always better to cooperate up front, Hank,
毕竟现在还是我们两个老朋友之间的对话
when it's just a conversation between two old friends.
否则事情会变得更正式
Otherwise things can get more formal.
更有争议
More contentious.
我说了  我不知道
Like I said, I don't know.
你看过一本叫《王子》的书吗
You ever read a book called "The Prince"?
是16世纪
Written by a cat
一个叫马基雅维里的家伙写的
named Machiavelli back in the 1500s.
我没看过
I haven't read that one.
我也没有
Well, me either.
不过里面有一句话很有道理
But there's one hell of a quote in that book.
大概意思是
Goes something like...
如果你想当国王
If you aim at the king,
那最好确保把他斩草除根
you better make damn sure you kill his ass.
嗯
Yeah.
这句话我很熟悉
Yeah, I am familiar with that one.
可是
See...
问题是  丹尼
The thing is, Denny,
我从没把你当目标
I never took aim at you.
只是你的一厢情愿
You only think I did.
我很肯定  律师一般会称之为
I'm pretty sure that's what lawyers would call
"无差异区别"
"A distinction without a difference."
晚安  汉克
Have a good night, Hank.
敬艾迪·格林
To Eddie Greene.
敬乔丹·阿特沃特
And to Jordan Atwater.
对
Yeah.
那孩子真有胆量
That kid's got guts.
作证  对抗一些可笑又根深蒂固的观念
Testifying, going against some ridiculous ingrained code...
很不容易
It's not easy.
你到底什么意思  海莉
What are you really saying, Hailey?
不是时候
Not the time, man.
不是时候吗  不
It's not the time? No, it's right.
我觉得正是时候  真的
I think it's the perfect time. Just say it.
好吧
All right.
行了  伙计
Just let it go, man.
行了
Let it go.
海莉  听我说
Hey, Hailey, look.
如果你想害我
If you're gonna throw me under the bus,
拜托事先说一声
just give me a heads up, huh?
我搞定了
I took care of it.
-什么意思  -投诉没了
- What do you mean? - Case went away.
就这么没了
It just went away?
我找到了那个目击者
I found the witness.
跟她聊了聊  她同意改变说法
I talked to her. She agreed to recant her story.
她就这么轻易同意了
She just agreed just like that?
这我可没说
I didn't say that.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不是为了你
I didn't do it for you.
明白
Copy that.
我...
So I...
我查了...
I ran that, uh...
你让我查的车牌号
Plate you were asking about.
是安东尼奥的朋友
Antonio's friend?
对
Yeah.
他是个州检察官
He's a State's Attorney.
叫内森·波特
A guy named Nathan Potter.
冉冉升起的新星
Rising star.
但是
But...
据说
Word is...
他跟你的老伙计丹尼·伍兹
He's done a lot of work with your pal,
一起合作了不少
Denny Woods.
你不会觉得安东尼奥...
You don't think Antonio's, uh...
今天早上我看到他跟波特说话了
The morning I saw him with this prosecutor Potter--
他说谎了
he lied.
他告诉我他去参加家长会了
He told me he was at some parent-teacher conference.
我就知道这么多
This much I know.
他们想对付我们  阿尔
They're coming after us, Al.
从各个方面
From all sides.
嗯
Yeah.
你来看周三的比赛吗
You coming to the game this Wednesday?
这次我会代表校队出赛
'Cause you know I'm getting some play time with varsity.
现场肯定会很精彩
It's gonna be crazy. It's gonna be hype.
我真的很激动
And I'm really excited for the showcase.
等等
Wait.
凯文  我们可以吃点甜点吗
Kev, can we get some dessert?
好啊
Yeah.
去吧
Go for it.
他们有奶昔吗
Do they have milkshakes?
你很紧张啊
You jumpy, huh?
没事  没事
I'm good, I'm good.
-是不是吓了一跳  凯文  -没事
- Little scared there, Kevin? - Not bad.
好  我要点冰淇淋
All right, I'm getting ice cream.
冰淇淋加巧克力酱
Ice cream with some chocolate sauce.
香蕉布丁  要跟我一起吃吗
Banana pudding. You wanna share with me?
我只吃过一次  味道...
I only had it once, it was...